<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sonar | Jay Patel</title>
    <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/tag/sonar/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://patel999jay.github.io/tag/sonar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>sonar</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright Jay Patel © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 11:58:49 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://patel999jay.github.io/images/icon_hu0f6e84e9ab2e4a261b0b52bea5579b58_240147_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>sonar</title>
      <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/tag/sonar/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow water Low-Frequency propagation Loss Predictions and measurements towards acoustic range characterization</title>
      <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/publication/shallow-water-low-frequency-propagation-loss-predictions-and-measurements-towards-acoustic-range-characterization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 11:58:49 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://patel999jay.github.io/publication/shallow-water-low-frequency-propagation-loss-predictions-and-measurements-towards-acoustic-range-characterization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Low-frequency ship noise negatively impacts marine ecosystems and interferes with marine mammal communications. In an effort to manage and reduce ship noise in marine environments, high-fidelity propagation loss measurements were conducted across multiple locations to develop a principled shallow water ranging methodology that improves the accuracy of shallow water ship ranging. This paper reports on a proposed propagation loss procedure and presents preliminary results from in-water tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;Calibrated acoustic projectors, driven by a programmable function generator, were used to simulate different types of ship noise. A surface-mounted, near-field hydrophone, and a pair of bottom-mounted, far-field hydrophones were used to receive the acoustic signals. Propagation loss (PL) was estimated from the near-field and far-field hydrophones to yield source level (SL) estimates. These SL estimates were compared with the calibrated acoustic projector&#39;s known source levels to verify the propagation loss accuracy. Future work will further develop PL estimation, resulting in a shallow water ranging technique with a performance comparable to that of deep water ranging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
