<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>author | Jay Patel</title>
    <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/author/author/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://patel999jay.github.io/author/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>author</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright Jay Patel © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 19:55:51 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://patel999jay.github.io/images/icon_hu0f6e84e9ab2e4a261b0b52bea5579b58_240147_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>author</title>
      <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/author/author/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of Low Profile Antenna for Point to Train Communication</title>
      <link>https://patel999jay.github.io/publication/development-of-low-profile-antenna-for-point-to-train-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 19:55:51 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://patel999jay.github.io/publication/development-of-low-profile-antenna-for-point-to-train-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34;&gt;A low profile, electrically small with omnidirectional vertically polarized radiation similar to a short monopole antenna is presented
for UHF (400-520 MHz) band. It has compact and mechanically stable structure for mounting on to the roof of the Heavy duty
vehicles such as Trains. It can also be employed with a ground plane (roof surface/rooftop) as in vehicle antenna is consider
advantageous because the desired direction of communication are mostly independent of the orientation of the vehicle. The proposed
antenna is made up of the compact size to reduce the overall antenna dimension. The simulation is carried out by using CST
Microwave Studio Program. The effect of the antenna parameters on the impedance bandwidth will be investigated. It is easily
embedded on the roof of the vehicle. Moreover, It has simple structure, low profile, easily mounted and relative good bandwidth
(BW). It is also shown that this antenna is nearly omnidirectional over a majority fraction of bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
